We need to find Kira Tinsley.
She either works for Red John
or she's about to become his next victim.
Who did this to you?
Tell me.
Jane, what did she say?
She told me Red John has
a tattoo on his left shoulder...
Three dots.
That's my leverage.
- "Jane."
- Hello, Lisbon.
"Jane, don't do this,
not without me."
Listen, I'm sorry.
"Jane, I am begging you.
You're in danger!"
- It's gonna be okay. I'm gonna be okay.
- "No, you're not."
"You do this and you're throwing
your life away."
- Bye, Lisbon.
- "Jane... No."
- "A tattoo?"
- Yes.
- That we can use to identify Red John?
That's great. So all we have to do is check
each one of the suspects one by one
until we find out
who has the tattoo.
- No.
- Why not?
Red John doesn't know
I know about the tattoo.
Okay.
So if we start checking suspects
it's very likely that Red John will find out.
And disappear before we have
a chance of getting him.
Exactly.
Then what do you wanna do?
Gather all five suspects together
at the same place, same time
- and then start checking for the tattoo.
- And how do we do that?
- We'll ask them.
- And you think they'll agree?
Wasn't planning on giving them
a choice.
Even so, there's a problem.
Bret Stiles...he's wanted by the F.B.I.
in connection to two homicides.
Yeah. Cold cases
from over 20 years ago.
You're kidding. After all this time
the F.B.I. is moving in now?
Well, they must have found
something new...
- Forensics, a witness.
- Well, where's Stiles?
Well, that's the thing.
Nobody knows.
Not even the F.B.I.
Stiles disappeared weeks ago.
- We'll find him.
- How?
I don't know, but we'll find him.
We have to.
- I'm on board with your plan.
- Good.
On one condition.
I wanna be there
when you reveal Red John.
- Okay.
- Seriously.
- I said okay.
- Yeah, but you didn't mean it.
Did I not?
How can you tell?
- This is non-negotiable, Jane.
- I agree 100%.
I think I've made myself clear, agents.
I have no knowledge of Bret Stiles'
whereabouts.
Yes Mr. Cooper, and we've
made it clear that we're not buying it.
Stiles leaves you
in charge of Visualize
but he keeps you in the dark
about where he's hiding?
Doesn't make sense.
Stiles has and always will put
the church's needs before his own.
This time is no different.
He doesn't want me to know
because he wants to protect me.
And because
he doesn't want to be found.
I doubt Bret Stiles is worried
about being found.
You seem confident.
Call it faith.
You see, Stiles' time in our...
Reality is limited.
As we speak he's preparing
his mind and body
for a departure from the confines
of our material world.
He's dying?
That is a very naive
very ignorant way of looking at it.
Bret Stiles is not dying.
Bret Stiles cannot die.
He is elevating himself
to another plane
one lesser men like ourselves
can only strive to reach.
And one some of us obviously
can't comprehend.
- Coffee... one cream, one sugar.
-Thanks, Russell.
Forensics is here
when you're ready.
Send them over.
Get his I.D. for me, will you?
You know how I am about heights.
Sure.
Oh, and, someone's here
to see you.
Thanks.
There's been a breakthrough
in the Red John investigation.
I have some new information.
Some very significant information.
- Okay. What is it?
- No, no. Not yet.
I'm not sure who I can trust.
I'm not even sure I can trust you.
Red John has some
very powerful allies.
Patrick, come on.
Okay, but not here.
Meet me at 8:00
on Thursday night.
Thursday? Why?
I need time to find
a safe place to meet.
Fine. Where?
- I'll let you know the day of.
- This is crazy.
I've made the mistake of underestimating
Red John a number of times now.
I don't wanna make
that mistake again.
If you want the information,
it's on my terms.
Okay.
Thursday night.
This is Sheriff McAllister.
Sheriff? Patrick Jane.
Hello, Patrick.
How are things?
Good. Good.
I'm calling because
I had a question.
Shoot.
Last month when I was in Napa
you said that you were at my disposal.
- Yes, I remember.
- Did you mean what you said?
- I like to think I'm a man of my word.
- Oh, I don't doubt it.
But can I count on you
for your help?
- "Can I count on you?"
- Of course.
Thursday night at 8:00
I'll need your help.
Well, then you've got it.
Thank you.
I'll let you know where to be
the day of.
- Patrick?
- Yeah?
This is about Red John,
isn't it?
Thursday night.
- They're ready for you, sir.
- Thank you, Evelyn.
Also, this came for you.
You are here tonight
to witness my ascension.
My ascension from this world
to a world beyond.
Do not mourn me, my children
for this is not a passing
but a departure.
And I promise...
I... Will... Return!
Listen to me, Don, you don't have
a mistress.
You have a vindictive screwball
who's about to ruin your life.
Yes, well, it's very lucky for you
my job is to fix problems
so here's what you're gonna do.
You are gonna write her
a check...
It is gonna be
a very big check...
And then you are gonna pray
that this problem goes away.
If it doesn't,
don't worry, Don.
There are plenty of ways
to keep a woman quiet. Okay?
All right.
I gotta go. All right.
Hello.
- You're late.
- It's good to see you, too, Teresa.
Uh, excuse me, can I get
coffee, black, please?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
So why am I here
at 8:00 a.m.?
I need help with an investigation.
What investigation?
- It's not important.
- Really? It is if you want my help.
I can't tell you.
Come on, Teresa.
I know you better than that.
What, you and Jane got something
going on with the Red John case?
- Maybe.
- "Maybe." yeah, right.
What is with all the secrecy?
Seriously, why are you
always holding out on me?
You don't think I'm Red John,
do you?
You do, don't you?
Tell you what.
You want to question me,
you arrest me.
Otherwise, you leave me
the hell out of this.
Sit down. Sit.
If asking's not gonna work,
I won't ask.
You're no longer
with the CBI.
You don't get the same protection
law enforcement gets.
- What, you threatening me?
- No, Jane is.
He wants to see you
tomorrow night.
If you don't show up, he will
assume you're Red John.
And, Ray, he will come after you.
You gotta be kidding me.
You know Jane.
You know what happened to him.
You know what Red John
did to him.
If I were you,
I wouldn't test him.
I'm not afraid
of Patrick Jane.
Well, what's the problem
with showing up?
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
For once and for all.
- What time?
- 8:00.
I'm not done.
There's one more thing
that I need.
You're killing me here.
- Stiles.
- Yeah?
- Where is he?
- I can't help you.
Come on, Ray, you've been
with Visualize for years.
I don't want to arrest him.
I just want to talk to him.
You do this,
and I will owe you.
And in your line of work, sooner or later
you're gonna need a favor.
So Ray Haffner told me that Stiles
uses a private jet to move
around the country undetected.
Belongs to a guy
named Ryan Parks.
Parks. Got it.
I'll check it out.
- Has Jane been in yet?
- No, I haven't heard from him.
Mr. Lamotte?
Yeah? Can I help you?
Agents Cho and Rigsby
from the CBI.
We were wondering if you could
answer a few questions for us.
Sure.
A G6 landed here late last night
tail number N550MT.
It would have been
around 11:00.
I remember.
What about it?
Do you know who was
on the flight?
No. Private aircraft aren't required
to provide passenger manifests.
Did you happen to see anyone
who was getting off the plane?
No. Sorry.
Oh, but whoever it was had
a car service pick him up.
They might be able
to help you.
You don't happen to have the name
of that car service by any chance?
Yes, I do.
So what happened
with the car service?
Well, they said that they picked up
a silver-haired man
with a British accent
from the airport last night.
- Stiles.
- We think so.
- Well, where'd he go?
- The address
was for the Ecuadorian
consulate in San Francisco.
Good job.
You two go and check it out.
You know what?
Van Pelt, why don't you go alone?
Stiles likes you. Maybe we can
use that to our advantage.
Is... There a problem?
- No.
- I'll be fine.
- I know.
- It's my job.
Hey.
- I love you.
- I know.
- Hey, Lisbon.
- Where are you?
- Oh, just running some errands.
- "Everything okay?"
Yeah, right as rain.
What's up?
"Haffner's in."
Good. What about Stiles?
Van Pelt may have a bead on his location.
She's checking it out now.
That leaves one more Red John
suspect left to talk to.
Yes. Bertram.
I'm on my way to his office.
- You want to meet me there?
- "All right."
Grace Van Pelt.
Well... How lovely to see you again.
Well... So, please sit.
- To what do I owe this pleasure?
- Jane.
He needs a favor.
Clever, him, sending you.
So exactly what can I do
for Patrick Jane?
He would like to meet with you.
Tomorrow night at 8:00.
You've changed since
we last met.
- You're married.
- Yes.
Oh, don't tell me you married
that genial oaf.
Oh. Oh, well.
Congratulations.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
So... Will you meet
with Jane?
Ah... You know, nothing would please
me more than to meet with him.
I mean, really,
I would love to. But...
Unfortunately,
my circumstances...
It's probably
not gonna happen.
You mean
because of the F.B.I.?
You have been doing
your homework.
They don't know I'm here.
Which means they don't know
you're here.
But they will if you don't agree
to meet with Jane.
You have changed,
haven't you?
Have you ever been
to Ecuador, by any chance?
No.
I was there...oh, God,
years and years ago
Doing missionary work.
Lovely people.
Oh, yeah, but-but...
There was a young man there...
he was underprivileged,
ferociously ambitious.
I saw something in him.
So I decided
to try and help him.
You know, I paid for his school fees
that sort of thing.
Nothing really much,
but wouldn't you know it?
All these years later, that same man
is now minister of state.
I'm happy for him.
Anyway, he invited me to stay in this
palatial consulate.
This morsel of foreign soil.
Foreign soil, which,
as you know
is outside the jurisdiction of you,
the F.B.I. and all U.S. law enforcement.
So, you see, Gracie your idle threats
are just that.
Well, it's been so lovely
seeing you again.
Please give my best
to Mr. Jane.
Close the door
on your way out!
- It's gonna be fine.
- Thanks. I feel a lot better.
Come on in.
We've made
a breakthrough, sir.
- In...
- The Red John case.
We're close to identifying him.
Well, then this
is fantastic news.
After all these years. You...
You really think you've got him?
I do.
I'll know the second you
have something concrete.
- You will, sir.
- And I want to be there when you end this.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Yeah, it's me.
I just had a very interesting
conversation with Patrick Jane.
How'd it go with Bertram?
- He's in. What about Stiles?
- Not so good.
- Did you find him?
- Yes.
Then what's the problem?
He's at the Ecuadorian consulate.
As long as he's there,
we can't touch him.
What do you want to do?
I'll handle Stiles.
He's not gonna come with you.
He doesn't have to.
I'll be persuasive.
What is that?
A shotgun. You sure it's big enough?
We need to talk
about tomorrow night.
- I've already told you.
- Just hear me out, please.
- You don't want me to be there.
- No, I don't.
You don't want to be there
because you think
I'm gonna try and stop you
from killing Red John.
Are you saying that you won't?
What I'm saying is some men...
Men like Red John...
They don't deserve a trial.
They don't deserve a jury.
They deserve what they have
coming to them.
Wait, let me get this straight.
After close to 20 years
working in law enforcement
you're just...
you're changing your mind?
About Red John? Yes.
I'm surprised, Lisbon.
- What, you don't believe me?
- Heavens, no.
You're the most honest
person I know.
You would never lie,
not about something like this.
- Right?
- Right.
- Tomorrow night then.
- Tomorrow night.
Patrick, dear boy.
Well, how are you?
Well, I'm not your boy.
Oh, I see. So this is
not a social meeting, eh?
You're gonna meet me
tonight at 8:00.
- Patrick...
- No, you listen to me.
You're gonna meet me
tonight at 8:00
or I'm gonna come back here,
and when I do
you will need more than these
walls to keep you safe.
Threats?
That's so out of character.
- I mean every word of it.
- Yes.
I believe you do.
But you see, Patrick
a dying man does not fear death.
Oh, please.
This charade might work on your disciples.
It doesn't work on me.
You think too highly of me.
Unfortunately
it's not a charade.
How long have you got?
It's spread to the blood.
There's nothing they can do.
I don't know...
two weeks, a month.
You see...
it's not personal.
It's just that...
my time now
is very precious.
I'm still gonna need you tonight.
For God sake, why?
What's so damned important?
Red John.
I'm close.
Closer than I've ever been.
Red John...
Look... nothing would give me more
pleasure than to be with you there tonight.
But?
There's more to this than you know.
There's... there's more keeping me here.
- The F.B.I.?
- Yeah, as a matter of fact.
You know,
they tracked me here.
They're just waiting for me to leave
so they can arrest me.
Look, I'm not choosing to stay here
but I'm trapped.
So the F.B.I.'s the only thing
that's keeping you here?
"Eyes up. We've got movement
at the front entrance."
"That's a Visualize car.
I think they're sneaking someone out."
"Get ready to move."
"Go now! Go! Go! Go!"
Don't move! Your hands
on your steering wheel.
Keep your hands
where we can see 'em.
Hello, gentlemen.
Something I can help you with?
Stiles is in.
We'd better get going.
We've got a long drive ahead of us.
Come on. Take him.
Well, then SAC P.D.'s just gonna
have to wait.
Look, I don't wanna pull rank...
but I will.
Kevin, I gotta call you back.
I'll be needing a car.
- What are we doing?
- I wanna see the sunset.
There's something I want
to tell you, Lisbon.
Something I should have said
a long time ago.
I want to thank you
for everything that you've done.
- You can thank me later.
- No, I...
I need to say this now.
You have... no idea
what you've meant to me.
What you mean to me.
Thank you.
I almost forgot.
I have a surprise for you.
Wait here.
Jane?
Jane!
Hello! Hey!
Hey! Stop!
Police.
My name is Teresa Lisbon. I am an agent
with the California Bureau of Investigation
and I need to borrow your car.
It's an emergency.
- What?! No way.
- Get out. Now. Come on.
- Come on.
- This is outrageous. I'm calling the police.
Good idea. Thanks.
Wh... damn!
- "Jane."
- Hello, Lisbon.
- Jane, don't do this, not without me.
- Listen, I'm sorry.
Jane, I am begging you.
You're in danger!
It's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna be okay.
No, you're not. You do this
and you're throwing your life away.
- Bye, Lisbon.
- "Jane..."
No.
Oh. Hello, Patrick.
Am I early?
No, no. Right on time.
Have a seat.
"9-1-1.
What's your emergency?"
This is agent Teresa Lisbon
with the California Bureau of Investigation.
I need officers
at 1309 cedar street in Malibu.
I have an agent who needs
immediate assistance.
I brought you five together
for a reason.
Some of you may know
that reason.
Some of you may have guessed.
But one of you here...
Is Red John.
What?! One of us?
One of us here is Red John?
Well, that's very interesting.
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
And that's what we're
gonna find out.
Wait, you're trying to say that one
of us in this room is a serial killer?
- I know it.
- No, this is crazy.
I can assure you, it's not.
Well, I can assure you
I'm not sticking around for this crap.
Sit down.
Do not move
toward the door.
No one is leaving.
Take it easy, Patrick.
Do I look distressed?
Don't.
I will shoot you.
That goes for the rest
of you as well.
Take out your weapons slowly,
place them on the floor
and push them toward me.
Thank you.
Okay, Patrick.
This is...
This is enough.
It's gone far enough.
No, we're just getting started.
I've waited ten years
for this moment.
All those years,
Red John has been smart.
One of you has been smart.
Careful.
But not this time.
This time,
you made a mistake.
Kira Tinsley told me something
before she passed.
She told me that her killer...
Red John...
Has a tattoo.
Three dots on his left arm.
On his shoulder.
And you all...
Are gonna show me...
Now.
Let's go. Come on.
That's it. Take it off.
Nonsense.
Very good.
It's not what you think.
- You got it wrong.
- Enough.
I'm not Red John.
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
Look... Here. Look.
On your feet.
Over with those two.
You stay there.
Okay, you three...
Over against that wall...
now.
"Wait! No!"
Jane!